# **Spencer Elswick**

Software Engineer

(502) 777.1050 · <u>spencerlelswick@gmail.com</u> · Louisville, Kentucky <u>spencerlelswick.netlify.app</u> · <u>linkedin.com/in/spencerlelswick</u> · <u>github.com/spencerlelswick</u>

Experienced developer with a background of over two years. I have a strong affinity for constructing intricate web applications. In my prior role, I provided support, maintenance, and added new features to business applications for UPS Airlines. Proficient in Agile methodologies, technology, and development, I'm eager to contribute to projects addressing complex business needs.

### **SKILLS**

Languages - JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Python, Java, Regex, EJS
Libraries and Frameworks - React, Angular, Tailwind, Bootstrap, styled-components, SCSS, Node, Express, Django, Spring
Database - SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MSSQL, Oracle, MySQL, SQLite
Tools and other - NPM, Git, TFS, REST, JSON, Postman, Maven, JUnit, Karma, Jasmine, Angular-CLI

#### **PROJECTS**

July 2023 - Oct 2023

## event.ly | MERN Stack | https://event-lv.netlifv.app/

- Created a map-based web application for finding and creating events to connect with people in their local communities
- Utilized MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) to build a full stack application with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls
- Implemented React components for map interactivity and panning linked to event list
- Added filter by category and date, as well as sort by popularity, name and proximity using the pythagorean theorem
- Leveraged third party APIs for tasks such as reverse geocoding lat/lon to physical addresses, and custom image selection
- Authenticated users with Google OAuth

#### Task Flow | Django/React Stack | https://task-flow-prod.netlify.app/

- Developed a task management application for team leaders to have high-level visibility of team task load
- Authorized two role levels of employee and manager, each with appropriate access rights and views
- Consolidated team task schedule into a high-level Gantt chart build with CSS and styled components to display relevant task information based on employee scheduled work time and unavailability
- Automatically adjust task schedules upon task start and end time changes within a task chain

#### Little Italy | MEN Stack | https://littleitaly-e2a8e59785f8.herokuapp.com/

- E-commerce style web application used to dynamically build custom pizzas for a fictitious pizza delivery store
- Styled with Bootstrap and contains an interactive pizza-builder with CSS animations
- Used Server side rendering with Node and Express to provide EJS templates to the client
- Implemented full CRUD functionality with MVC design pattern
- Modeled data structures with Mongoose database schema

## Personal Portfolio Website | React | https://spencerlelswick.netlify.app/

Portfolio website built with React and styled with Tailwind CSS

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Application Developer**, UPS Flight and Crew | Louisville, KY

Mar 2018 - Dec 2020

In this role I was an Application Developer for the Flight and Crew DST team at UPS Airlines. Primarily, my team was tasked with combining legacy monolithic flight applications into modern front end web applications with microservice oriented backends.

- Over 2 years experience working in a corporate environment as a full stack developer using primarily Angular/Spring stack
- Provided input and support for full systems life cycle management activities (analyses, technical requirements, design, coding, testing, implementation of software)
- Performed tasks within planned durations and established deadlines defined in team foundation server (TFS)
- Extensive experience in the development of single page applications (SPA) using HTML, CSS, TypeScript, Angular 2
- Used RxJS observable library to handle async data streams
- Experience with unit testing with Karma, Jasmine and JUnit
- Created and maintained application documentation and diagrams
- Implemented bug-fixes as reported by users and quality assurance
- Working experience with backend technologies primarily with Java and Spring Framework
- Database experience with MSSQL, and Oracle for CRUD operations
- Planned and provided security related maintenance such as certs, encryption clients, authentication, and password rotation
- Managed application environment changes, e.g. WebLogic migration to OpenShift
- Planned, monitored and executed application deployments
- Provided 24/7 application support on a weekly team rotation
- Verified application health and stability daily, and after incidents

## Telecommunications Analyst, UPS Global Network Systems | Louisville, KY

Mar 2015 - Feb 2018

- Monitored network alerts, devices, and traffic utilization
- Planned maintenance, network software upgrades, adds/removes of network equipment
- Provided protocol analysis for data center and airline networks
- Managed network outages and incidents
- 24/7 phone support for network related activities
- Automation scripting with Python
- Developed a full stack web application for issue tracking, turnover, and case written in C#.NET / AngularJS

### **Technician III,** UPS Automation Support Group | Louisville, KY

Aug 2014 - Feb 2015

- Provided incident response for critical airline infrastructure
- Monitored server and database logs in a RHEL/Oracle environment
- Performed routine and EOD/BOD database and server maintenance for operational readiness

# Technician, UPS Airline Application Support Helpdesk | Louisville, KY

Jul 2012 - Jul 2014

- Monitored critical IT infrastructure via alert console and logs
- Provided application, server and network support in a 24/7 call center striving for 100% operational uptime
- Managed, tracked, and documented incidents in a case system

## **EDUCATION**

# **GENERAL ASSEMBLY**

Software Engineering Fellow

Oct 2023

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 12-week full-time program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

## WESTERN KENTUCKY UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science in Computer Information Technology

Dec 2019